Preliminary Guide to the Africa News Service (Durham, N.C.) Leroy T. Walker Africa News Service Archive, 1952-1998 and undated (bulk 1952-1994)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- U.S. - Africa Groups (Box 256)
  - "C" (Box 259)
    - Council for Christian Social Action (Box 260)
    - Council on African Affairs (Box 260)
  - "D" (Box 260)
    - Denver Project Southern Africa (Box 260)
    - Detroit Committee for the Liberation of Africa (Box 260)
    - Diversified Systems Group (Box 260)
  - "E" (Box 260)
    - Episcopal Churchpeople for a Free South Africa, 1968-1991, (4 folders) (Box 260)
    - Emergency Fund for Southern Africa (Box 260)
    - Eritreans for Liberation in North America (Box 260)
    - Eritrean People's Solidarity Committee (Box 260)
    - Eritrean Relief Committee (Box 260)
    - Eritrean People's Solidarity Committee (Box 260)
    - Ethiopian Student Union in North America (Box 260)
  - "F" (Box 260)
    - Fifth Commission (Box 260)
    - Free Southern Africa Committee (Box 260)
    - Friends of Angola (Box 260)
    - Friends of the Christian Institute (Box 260)
    - Friends of Liberia (Box 260)
    - Friends of Transkei (Box 260)
  - "G" (Box 260)
    - Groundswell USA (Box 260)
    - Gulf Boycott Coalition (Box 260)
  - "H" (Box 261)
    - Habari, 1976, Dec.-1978, June (Box 261)
    - Harrisburg Committee for Solidarity with African Liberation (Box 261)
  - "I" (Box 261)
    - IDAFSA (Box 261)
    - International Committee for Defense of African Workers (Box 261)
    - International Student Support Committee (Box 261)
    - ITT Boycott (Box 261)
    - Institute for Coordinated African American Research (ICAAR) (Box 261)
    - International Freedom Mobilization (Box 261)
    - Intermews Media Services (Box 261)
  - "J" (Box 261)
    - Jesuit Refugee Service in America (Box 261)
  - "L" (Box 261)
    - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law (Southern Africa Project) (Box 261)
    - Liberation Support Movement (Box 261)
    - Liberation Support Movement (Bay Area) (Box 261)
    - List of Canada & U.S. organizations in South Africa (Box 261)
    - Lutheran Coalition on Southern Africa (Box 261)
  - "M" (Box 261)
    - Madison Area Committee on Southern Africa, 1971-1980 (2) (Box 261)
    - Madison Conference (Box 261)
    - Massachusetts Conference Task Force on Southern Africa (Box 261)
    - Medical Aid for Foreign Groups (Box 261)
    - Mozambique Education Fund, Inc. (Box 261)
    - Mozambican Student's Unions (UNEMO-USA) (Box 261)
    - Mozambique Film Project (Box 261)
    - Mozambique Institute (Box 261)
    - Mozambique Solidarity Action (Box 261)
    - Mozambique Solidarity Committee (Box 261)
    - Mozambique Support Group (Box 261)
    - MPLA Printship Project (Box 261)
    - MPLA Solidarity Committee (Box 261)
    - Museum of African Art (Box 261)
  - "N" (Box 261)
    - Namibia Support Group (Box 261)
    - Nashville African Liberation Committee (Box 261)
    - National Anti-Imperialist Committee in Solidarity with Africa (Box 262)
    - National Black Human Rights Campaign (Box 262)
    - National Coalition to support African Liberation (Box 262)
    - National Committee to Free SASO 9 (Box 262)
    - National Museum of African Art (Box 262)
    - National Liberation Struggles Support Committee (Arise) (Box 262)
    - National Union of Angolan Students (Box 262)
    - New Africa Liberation Support Committee (Box 262)
    - New York (Box 262)
    - Northeast Committee for the Liberation of Southern Africa (Box 262)
  - "O" (Box 262)
    - Operation Bootstrap Africa (Box 262)
    - Operation Crossroads Africa (Box 262)
    - Operation Namibia (Box 262)
    - Organization of South Africans in the Americas (Box 262)
  - "P" (Box 262)
    - P.A.I.G.C. Support Committee (Box 262)
    - Pan African Association (Box 262)
    - Pan African Congress (Box 262)
    - Pan African Liberation Committee (Box 262)
    - Pan African Skills Project (Box 262)
    - Pan African Students Organization in the United States (Box 262)
    - Patrice Lumumba Coalition (Box 262)
    - Phelps Stokes Fund (Box 262)
    - Pygmy Fund (Box 262)
  - "R" (Box 262)
    - Rains (see US Groups IFCO) (Box 262)
    - Red Star Collective (Box 262)
  - "S" (Box 262)
    - SAMRAF (Box 262)
    - SANSIC (Box 262)
    - SASASAS (Box 262)
    - Schomburg Center (Box 262)
    - South Africa Boycott Project (see US: African Groups: Action for World Community) (Box 262)
    - South African Crisis Coordinating Committee (Box 262)
    - South African Education Program (Box 262)
    - Southern Africa Anti-Mercenary Coalition (Box 262)
    - Southern Africa Christian Alliance (Box 262)
    - Southern Africa Committee (Box 262)
    - Southern Africa Education Program (Box 262)
    - Southern Africa Media Center (Box 262)
    - Southern Africa Organizing Committee (Box 262)
    - Southern Africa Solidarity Committee (Box 262)
    - Southern Africa Support Committee (Box 263)
    - Southern African Support Project (Box 263)
    - Southern Africa Working Group (Box 263)
    - Southern African Research Association (SARA) (Box 263)
    - Southern Association of Africanists (Box 263)
    - Student Organization for Black Unity (Box 263)
    - Study Committee on U.S. Policy Toward Southern Africa (Box 263)
    - Sudan Interior Mission (Box 263)
    - Support Committee--Sahara (Box 263)
    - SWASIA--North Africa (Box 263)
  - "T" (Box 263)
    - Task Force on South Africa--Philadelphia (Box 263)
    - TCHUBA (Box 263)
    - Temporary Organizing Committee for National Conference in Solidarity with African Liberation (Box 263)
    - This is the Time (Box 263)
    - Trans-Africa (Box 263)
  - "U" (Box 263)
    - Union of Liberian Associations to the Americas (ULAA) (Box 263)
    - UNEMO-USA (see Mozambican Student Union) (Box 263)
    - U.S.-Congo Friendship Committee (Box 263)
    - U.S. Out of Angola Committee (Box 263)
    - USSALEP (Leadership Exchange Program) (Box 263)
  - "W" (Box 263)
    - Washington Office on Africa, thru 1982, 1988-, (2 folders) (Box 263)
    - Washington Task Force on African Affairs (Box 263)
    - West Africa Emergency Relief (see: Groups Community Churches of America) (Box 263)
    - Western Sahara Campaign, USA (Box 263)
  - "Y" (Box 263)
    - Youth Organization for Black Unity (Box 263)
  - "Z" (Box 263)
    - Zanu Solidarity Committee (Box 263)
    - Zanu Support Committee (Box 263)
    - Zaiare Research Institute (Box 263)
    - Zimbabwe Students Scholarship Fund (Box 263)
    - Zimbabwe Relief Coalition (Box 263)
    - Friends of Zimbabwe (Box 263)
- U.S. Groups (Box 263)
  These groups do not have Africa-related concerns as their primary focus, although their efforts may include African issues. The groups represent a wide range of entities including foundations; political, religious, and humanitarian organizations; universities; unions; community groups; and branches of international organizations. Among the groups are the Ford Foundation, All People's Congress, National Council of Churches, Bread for the World, Peoples College, United Mine Workers, and Coalition for a New Foreign and Military Policy. Preceding the alphabetical list of group names is one folder for each letter of the alphabet that contains materials on several groups. This file was maintained when there was only one or two articles about a group and did not yet warrant starting a separate folder. There are related files in series, "U.S. Africa Groups," "North Carolina," and "World."
  - "A" (Box 264)
    - Adventist Development and Relief Agency (Box 264)
    - Action for World Community (South Africa Boycott) (Box 264)
    - AID (Box 264)
      - General (Box 264)
      - ADRA Eithiopian Relief Fund (Box 264)
      - Bread for the World (Box 264)
      - Catholic Relief Service (Box 264)
      - CARE (Box 264)
      - Church World Service (Box 264)
      - Food for the Hungry (Box 264)
      - Food for Peace (Box 264)
      - Grassroots International (Box 264)
      - International Christian Aid (Box 264)
      - International Voluntary Services, Inc. (Box 264)
      - List of Groups (Box 264)
      - Meals for Millions Foundation (Box 264)
      - Misc. (Box 264)
      - Oxfam (Box 264)
      - Private Agencies in International Development (Box 264)
      - Partnership for Production (Box 264)
      - Save the Children (Box 264)
      - Techno Serve (Box 264)
      - World Food Day (Box 264)
      - World Hunger Year (Box 264)
      - World Relief (Box 264)
      - World Neighbors (Box 264)
      - World Vision (Box 264)
    - All People's Congress (Box 265)
    - American Foreign Service Association (AFSA) (Box 265)
    - American Enterprise Institute (2folders) (Box 265)
    - AFL-CIO (Box 265)
    - American Friends Service Committee, 1978-1993 (Box 265)
      - Listen Real Loud (Box 265)
    - American Legion (Box 265)
    - American Library Association: Black Caucus (Box 265)
    - American Management Association (Box 265)
    - American Security Council (Box 265)
    - American Universities Field Staff (Box 265)
    - Americans for Democratic Action (ADA) (Box 265)
    - Amnesty International (see World Groups--Amnesty International) (Box 265)
    - Aspen Institute (Box 265)
  - "B" (Box 265)
    - Better World Society (Box 265)
    - Black Economic Development Conference (Box 265)
    - Black Pride (Box 265)
    - Black Women's Community Development Foundation (Box 265)
    - Black Workers Organizing Committee (Box 265)
    - Brookings Institute (Box 265)
    - Bretton Woods Committee (Box 265)
  - "C" (Box 266)
    - Campaign for Political Rights (Box 266)
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (Box 266)
    - Carter Presidential Center (Box 266)
    - Center for Popular Economics (Box 266)
    - Center for Strategic and International Studies (Box 266)
    - Center of Concern; Center of Focus (Box 266)
    - Christian Anti Communism Crusade (Box 266)
    - Citizens Energy Corporation (Box 266)
    - Coalition for a New Foreign and Military Policy, thru 1988, (2 folders) (Box 266)
    - Committee of Returned Volunteers (Box 266)
    - Communist League (Box 266)
    - Communist Party, USA (CPUSA) (Box 266)
      - Africa Program. (Box 266)
    - Conservative Action Foundation (Box 266)
    - CORE (Box 266)
    - Coporate Information Center (Box 266)
    - Council for a Livable World (Box 266)
    - Council on Economic Priorities (Box 266)
    - Covert Action (Box 266)
    - Crippled Eagle Foundation (Box 266)
    - Cultural Survival (Box 266)
  - "D" (Box 266)
    - Data Center (Box 266)
    - D.C. Bank Campaign (Box 266)
    - Defense Committee (Box 266)
    - The Development G.A.P. (Box 266)
    - Disarm Education Fund (Box 266)
  - "E" (Box 266)
    - Earthwatch (Box 266)
    - Economic Development Bureau (Box 266)
    - Edenite Society (Box 266)
  - "F" (Box 266)
    - Fahari (Box 266)
    - Family Health International (Box 266)
    - FHI: AIDSTECH (Box 266)
    - Fifth Estate (Counter-Spy) (Box 266)
    - Food First (Box 267)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 267)
    - Foreign Policy Association (Box 267)
    - Foreign Policy Research Institute (Box 267)
    - Foundation for American Communications (Box 267)
    - Foundation for Economic Education (Box 267)
    - Freedom Forum (Box 267)
    - Freedom House (Box 267)
    - Fund for an Open Society (Box 267)
  - "G" (Box 267)
    - Global Exchange (Box 267)
    - Goldman Environmental Prize (Box 267)
    - Greenpeace (Box 267)
    - Gray Panthers (Box 267)
  - "H" (Box 267)
    - Habitat for Humanity (Box 267)
    - Harlem Third World Trade Institute, "Trade Winds" (Box 267)
    - Heifer Project International (Box 267)
    - Helen Keller Institute (Box 267)
    - Heritage Foundation (Box 267)
    - Highlander Research & Educational Center (Box 267)
    - Hoover Institution (Box 267)
    - Hudson Institute (Box 267)
    - Hunger Project, 1987-1994 (Box 267)
  - "I" (Box 267)
    - IDOC/North America (Box 267)
    - IFCO (Box 268)
    - Institute for Food and Development Policy, see also Food First (Box 268)
    - Institute for Foreign Policy Analysis (Box 268)
    - Institute for World Order (Box 268)
    - Institute of the Black World (Box 268)
    - Institute of International Education (Box 268)
    - Institute for Policy Studies (Box 268)
    - Interaction (Box 268)
    - International Center for Law in Development (Box 268)
    - International Finace Corporation (Box 268)
    - International Freedom Foundation (Box 268)
      - 435 Watch (Namibia) (Box 268)
      - Angola Peace Monitor (Box 268)
    - International Food Policy Research Institute (Box 268)
    - International League for Human Rights (Box 268)
    - International Human Rights Law Group(IHRC) (Box 268)
    - International Longshore Men's & Warehousemen's Union, Africa's Programs (Box 268)
    - International Oil Working Group (Box 268)
    - International Peace Academy (Box 268)
    - International Rescue Committee (Box 268)
    - International Socialist Organization (Box 268)
    - International Studies Association (Box 268)
    - International Third World Legal Studies Association (Box 268)
    - Investor Responsibility Research Center (Box 268)
  - "J" (Box 269)
    - John Birch Society (Box 269)
    - Journal of the Northwest (Box 269)
  - "K" (Box 269)
    - Klu Klux Klan (KKK) (Box 269)
  - "L" (Box 269)
    - Lawyer's Committee for Rights Under Law (Box 269)
    - Lawyer's Committee for Human Rights (Box 269)
    - Liberty Lobby (Liberty Letter, Rockefeller Record, America First) (Box 269)
  - "M" (Box 269)
    - Mass Party Organizing Committee (Box 269)
    - Middle East Research Information Project (Box 269)
    - Middle East Resource Center (Box 269)
    - Minnesota Lawyers International Human Rights Committee (Box 269)
    - Mobilization for Survival (Box 269)
  - "N" (Box 269)
    - NAACP (Box 269)
    - NAAIC (Box 269)
    - NARMIC (Box 269)
    - National Association of Manufacturers (Box 269)
    - National Black Independent Political Party (Box 269)
    - National Black News Service (Box 269)
    - National Caucus of Labor Committees (NCLC) (Box 269)
    - National Committee for an Effective Congress (Box 269)
    - National Coalition of 100 Black Women (Box 269)
    - National Committee for Monetary Reform (Box 269)
    - National Committee to Overturn the Bakke Decision (Box 269)
    - National Conservative Political Action Committee (Box 269)
    - National Council for Black Studies (Box 269)
    - National Council of Negro Women (Box 269)
    - National Democratic Institute for Interational Affairs (Box 269)
    - National Education Association (Box 269)
    - National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee (Box 269)
    - National Endowment for Democracy (Box 269)
    - National Lawyers Guild and Midnight Special (Box 269)
    - National Student's Association (Box 269)
    - Natural Resources Defense Council, Inc. (Box 269)
    - New American Movement (Box 270)
    - NEH (Box 270)
    - New Directions (Box 270)
    - The New School for Democratic Management (Box 270)
    - New World Resource Center (Box 270)
    - Nieman Foundation (Box 270)
    - North American Congress on Latin America (NACLA) (Box 270)
  - "O" (Box 270)
    - Olin Foundation (Box 270)
    - Operation Smile (Box 270)
    - Overseas Development Council (Box 270)
    - Overseas Development Network (Box 270)
    - Overseas Private Investment Corporation (Box 270)
  - "P" (Box 270)
    - Pacific Studies Centers (Box 270)
    - Panus Institute (Box 270)
    - Patrick's Walk (Box 270)
    - People for the American Way (Box 270)
    - People's Anti-War Mobilizer (Box 270)
    - Phelps Stokes Fund (Box 270)
    - Political Risk Services (Box 270)
    - Population Reference Bureau (Box 270)
    - Population Services International (Box 270)
    - Prairie Fire Organizing Committee (Box 270)
    - PUSH for Excellence (Box 270)
  - "R" (Box 270)
    - Rainbow Lobby (Box 270)
    - Ray O Light (Box 270)
    - ReCon (Box 270)
    - Reebok International (Box 270)
    - Religion (Box 270)
      - African Methodist Church (Box 270)
      - American Lutheran Church (Box 270)
      - Baptist Church (Box 270)
      - Black Jewish Information Center (Box 271)
      - Catholic Workers (Box 271)
      - Christian Voice (Box 271)
      - Clergy and Laity Concerned (Box 271)
      - Codel (Box 271)
      - Council of Churches of City of New York (Box 271)
      - Council of Churches of Greater Washington (Box 271)
      - Council on Religion & International Affairs (Box 271)
      - Episcopal Church (Box 271)
      - Institute on Church in Urban Industrial Society (Box 271)
      - Interfaith Action for Economic Justice (Box 271)
      - Interfaith Committee on Social Responsibility in Investments (Box 271)
      - Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility (Box 271)
      - Interreligious Foundation for Community Orgainization (Box 271)
        - Africa Programs (Box 271)
      - Islamic Society of Georgia (Box 271)
      - Jehovah's Witnesses (Box 271)
      - Lutheran Church (Box 271)
      - Mary Knoll (Box 271)
      - National Council of Churches (Box 271)
        - Africa Programs thru 1976, 1977-1991, (2 folders) (Box 271)
        - Consultation on Southern Africa (Box 271)
        - The Fifth Commission (Box 271)
      - National Student Christian Federation (Box 272)
      - New York State Council of Churches (Box 272)
      - North American Region of World Student Christian Federation (Box 272)
      - Peoples Temples (Box 272)
      - Reformed Church in America (Box 272)
      - Religious Christian Church (Box 272)
      - Religious News Service (Box 272)
      - Roman Catholic Church (Box 272)
      - Scientologists (Box 272)
      - Southern Christian Leadership Conference (Box 272)
      - Unitarian Universalist (Box 272)
      - United Christian Missionary Society (Box 272)
      - United Church Board for World Ministries (Box 272)
      - United Church of Christ (Box 272)
        - Africa Programs (Box 272)
      - United Methodist Church (Box 272)
        - Africa Programs thru 1979, 1980- (Box 272)
        - Africa University (Box 272)
        - "News" (Box 272)
      - United Presbyterian Church (Box 273)
        - Africa Programs (Box 273)
      - United States Catholic Conference (Box 273)
      - University Christian Movement (Box 273)
    - Resist (Box 273)
    - Resolution (Box 273)
    - Resources (Box 273)
    - The Rest of the News (Box 273)
    - Revolutionary Communist Party, USA (RCP) (Box 273)
    - Revolutionary Student Brigade (Fightback) (Box 273)
    - Rodale Research Center (Box 273)
    - Rodale Institute & Press (Box 273)
    - Rural Advancement Fund International (Box 273)
  - "S" (Box 273)
    - Sane (Box 273)
    - Social Democrats, USA (Box 273)
    - Socialist Labor Party (Box 273)
    - Socialist Party, USA (Box 273)
    - Southern Poverty Law Center (Box 273)
    - Southerners for Economic Justice (Box 273)
    - Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee (SNCC) (Box 273)
    - Students for a Democratic Society (SDS): Africa Programs (Box 273)
    - Student National Medical Association (Box 273)
  - "T" (Box 273)
    - Taxation With Representation (Box 273)
    - Teamsters (Box 273)
    - Technical/ITD (Box 273)
    - Third World Awareness Workshop Team (Box 273)
    - Third World Forum (Box 273)
    - Third World Fund (Box 273)
    - Third World People's Coalition (Box 273)
    - Third World Reader Service (Box 273)
    - Third World Reports (Box 273)
    - Third World Women's Alliance (Box 273)
    - Tidewater Africans (see also Defense Committee, G.I. Movement East) (Box 273)
    - Toward Freedom (Box 273)
    - The Travelling Folk School (Box 273)
    - Treaty Council News (Box 273)
    - Trees for the Future (Box 273)
    - Tricontinental Film Center (Box 273)
    - Tricontinental News Service (Box 273)
  - "U" (Box 273)
    - Unions: (Box 273)
      - AFSCME (Box 273)
      - United Auto Workers (Box 273)
      - United Electrical Workers (Box 273)
      - United Farm Workers (Box 273)
      - United Mine Workers (UMWA) (Box 273)
        - Brookside Mine Strike (Box 273)
        - Harlan Strike (Box 273)
        - South African Coal Campaign (Box 273)
      - United Steelworkers (Box 274)
    - United Nations Association of the USA (Box 274)
    - US-China Peoples Friendship Association (Box 274)
    - US Institute of Peace (Box 274)
    - US Labor Party--New Solidarity (Box 274)
    - Universities (Box 274)
      - Amherst College (Box 274)
      - Boston University (Box 274)
      - California, University of = UCLA, (2 folders) (Box 274)
      - Chicago, University of (Box 274)
      - College of Holy Cross (Box 274)
      - Columbia (Box 274)
      - Cornell (Box 274)
      - Dartmouth (Box 274)
      - Florida, University of (Box 274)
      - Georgetown (Box 274)
      - Harvard (Box 274)
      - Howard (Box 274)
      - Illinois, University of (Box 274)
      - Indiana University (Box 274)
      - Johns Hopkins University (Box 274)
      - Kalamazoo College (Box 274)
      - Meharry Medical College (Box 274)
      - Michigan State University (Box 274)
      - Michigan, University of (Box 274)
      - Minnesota, University of (Box 274)
      - Morehouse College (Atlanta) (Box 274)
      - New York State University at Albany (Box 274)
      - Northwestern University (Box 274)
      - Oregon, University of (Box 274)
      - Pennsylvania State University (Box 274)
      - People's College (Box 274)
      - Roanoke College (Box 274)
      - Stanford (Box 274)
      - Syracuse (Box 274)
      - Valdosta State College (Box 274)
      - Virginia, University of (Box 274)
      - Wisconsin, University of (Box 274)
    - Universities: Yale University (Box 275)
    - Urban League (Box 275)
  - "V" (Box 275)
  - "W" (Box 275)
    - War and Peace Foundation (Box 275)
    - Winock International (Box 275)
    - Women's Commission for Refugee Women and Childen (Box 275)
    - Women's International Network (Box 275)
    - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (Box 275)
      - Africa Programs (Box 275)
    - Woodlands Conference (Box 275)
    - World Future Society (Box 275)
    - World Mercy Fund (Box 275)
    - World Peace Foundation (Box 275)
    - World Resources Institute (Box 275)
    - World Church Service (Box 275)
    - World Harvest Fund (see Technoserve) (Box 275)
    - Worldview (see Council on Religion & International Affairs) (Box 275)
    - Worldwatch Institute (Box 275)
    - YMCA (Box 275)
    - YWCA (Box 275)
    - Young Americans for Freedom (YAF) (Box 275)
    - Young Socialist Alliance (Box 275)
  - "Z" (Box 275)
    - Zodiac (Box 275)
- U.S. Media (Box 275)
  ANS has a strong interest in how Africa is covered by the U. S. media. This series includes information on mainstream, alternative, minority and special interest publications as well as radio and television. The files provide information about the type and amount (usually lack of) coverage given to African issues by U.S. media. There are also compilations of editorials that reveal an individual media organization's viewpoint on Africa. Over time, such editorials were filed under the appropriate subject rather than by the media organization. Related materials about individual journalists and publishers are located in the series, "Persons."
  - ABC (Box 275)
  - Accuracy in Media (AIM) (Box 275)
  - Africa Coverage thru 1989, 1990-93, (3 folders) (Box 275)
    - South Africa (Box 275)
      - ABC (Box 275)
    - West Sahara (Box 275)
  - Africa Resources (Box 275)
  - Africa Today (Box 275)
  - Africa Word News Network (Box 275)
  - African Index (Box 275)
  - Alternative (Box 275)
  - Alternative Press Syndicate (Box 275)
  - American Newspaper Publisher's Association (Box 275)
  - American Spectator (Box 275)
  - Amsterdam News (Box 275)
  - Arizona Project (Box 275)
  - Associated Press (Box 275)